

KRISTINA HAMILTON

hamilton.kristina@gmail.com | 320-267-6313

Maple Grove, MN 55369

PORTFOLIO

LinkedIn: /kristina-hamilton-355524169/| Portfolio: kayOs.github.io/Portfolio/ |

GitHub: /github.com/Kay0s

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A full-stack web developer who thinks user first. Drawing from a vast background in marketing and user experience obtained from an education at the University of Minnesota Duluth and experience in sales. Recently earned a certificate in full stack development from the University of Minnesota, with newly honed skills in JavaScript, CSS, and Web APIs. A proven passion for ease-of-use in design and innovative solutions.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages:

- JavaScript ES6+
- CSS3
- HTML5

Applications:

GitHub

Tools:

- Node
- Query
- Bootstrap
- Bulma

Other Skills:

- Marketing strategies
- Interpersonal communication
- Goals and performance coaching
- EDI Software
- Relationship building
- Technical Analysis
- Project organization
- Problem resolution
- Project Management

PROJECTS

Anemoi | https://github.com/Kay0s/weather-jamz | https://kay0s.github.io/weather-jamz/

- Summary: An app for a weather and music enthusiast that generates the current weather and a music video playlist based on current weather data.
- Role: Front end designer
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, APIs, and Bulma

Weather Dashboard | https://github.com/KayOs/Server-Side-APIs-Weather-Dashboard | https://kayOs.github.io/Server-Side-APIs-Weather-Dashboard/

- Summary: Weather app that provides current and future weather forecasts in cities.
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, API, Bootstrap, and Font Awesome

Work Day Scheduler | https://github.com/Kay0s/Work-Day-Scheduler-Using-Moment.js | https://kay0s.github.io/Work-Day-Scheduler-Using-Moment.js/

- Summary: A responsive scheduler that utilizes JQuery and Moment.js to save and retrieve information from client-side storage
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Moment.is, and API

WORK HISTORY

Sales Account Manager | Blakeway Panorama - Minnetonka, MN

04/2016 - CURRENT

- Partnered with Marketing E-commerce manager for online set-up of items and analysis of sales
- Brought about industry-leading results by applying strategic industry knowledge and leadership skills.
- Worked diligently to resolve unique and recurring complaints, promoting loyalty and enhancing operations.

Store Manager | GameStop, Inc - Plymouth, Minnesota

01/2008 - 04/2016

- Utilized research and analytical skills by analyzing sales trends and profit and loss reports to develop marketing initiatives and marketing strategies, most notably the "trade bag" which lead to a 10% sales and trade of pre-owned gaming and consumer electronics growth from the previous year.
- Through successfully driving sales, recorded annual sales in excess of \$1 million.
- Promoted team collaboration, performance and efficiency by fostering healthy environments focused on mutual success.

Assistant Store Manager | GameStop, Inc - Maple Grove, 01/2006 - 01/2007 Minnesota

EDUCATION

University Of Minnesota Duluth, Duluth, MN

Bachelor of Arts: Marketing

University Of Minnesota - Twin Cities, Saint Paul, MN Certificate, Full Stack Web Development

AWARDS

- Personally awarded Gamestop's highest honor, The Gold Standard, in customer service.
- Won sales contest to earn a trip to Ireland